Saurav Kumar

+918272888743 | sauravkumar01328@gmail.com | LinkedIn

Professional Summary

Front-end Developer and Graphic Designer with over 2 years of experience in creating responsive and Userfriendly websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, React-redux, Photoshop, Illustrator and Canva. Committed to delivering high-quality work that meets and exceeds client expectations.

Experience

Front-end Developer | L&T Technology Services
Web Development Intern | Arbazo Infotech Pvt Ltd
Jun 2024 – Present
Mar 2022 - Apr 2022

Skills

- Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, React-Redux
- Design: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Canva, Figma, Blender
- Operating Systems: OS Installation, Data Backup, Password Recovery

Education

Diploma in Computer Science & Engineering
 New Government Polytechnic Patna-13
Matriculation
 St. Lawrence Academy
Aug 2021 – Sep 2024
 May 2020 – July 2021

Certifications

 Entrepreneurship, Introduction to IoT, Introduction to Cybersecurity, PCAP: Programming Essentials in Python, Introduction to Networks (CISCO), Introduction to Computers (Spoken Tutorial, IIT Bombay)

Projects

- College Website Clone: Developed a responsive website that replicates the features and design of NGP Patna-13 using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap
- Object-Avoiding Car: Built a smart car capable of detecting and avoiding obstacles using Arduino Uno, ultrasonic sensors, servo motors, and LEDs.